In this tutorial, I will share with you how to make a pop-up card in Marvelous Designer.
Before we use Marvelous Designer to make a pop-up card, I created a simple pop-up card opening animation in Autodesk Maya.
I will reverse this animation to make it a pop-up card closing animation.
Because in the open state of the pop-up card, the elements in the scene are simpler.
Now we use FBX format to export this animation and use it as a virtual model in Marvelous Designer.
The first element in the scene we are going to make is the house model.
In the 2D window, draw various board shapes like paper film.
You can pause the screenshot and then import it as a background picture to draw the board.
Then arrange the board in the 3D window.
Use the smooth flip function to flip the board in the 3D window
to make the board face outwards.
Use the fold arrangement tool to fold the inner lines of the board to build the house.
In the attribute editor, you can manually set the fold angle to 90 degrees to ensure that these inner lines of the fold are aligned with the straight corner.
Repeat the steps until you have completed all the places where you need to fold.
After you have completed all the places where you need to fold,
make sure that the boards are in the correct position in the 3D window and that the places where you need to fold are also in the correct position.
In the 3D window, use the smooth flip tool to fold the corresponding lines together,
just like when you use glue to stick them together in real life.
In the hardboard, use the application to increase the fold effect to start the simulation.
We can set the fold angle for the inner line on the side of the house,
so that it folds inwards.
Use the edit board tool to select the inner line on the side,
and set the fold angle to 180 degrees in the attribute editor,
so that it folds inwards.
Then, use the edit line tool to set the fold angle of the corner of the house to 90 degrees,
so that the corner becomes a straight corner.
Setting the inner line and the fold angle of the line can fold the board according to their own needs.
Finally, in order to simulate the card effect,
adjust the physical properties of the fabric to Trim Hardwear.
This fabric is a harder type.
Open the simulation to check the effect.
I will use the beach ball board to make a pumpkin.
Arrange these boards in a circle.
Use the Trim Hardwear tool to merge the boards together.
Select all the boards, set the pressure value, and start the simulation.
Next, I will cut off a small part of the top to make the pumpkin ground.
Use the 3D board tool to make a circular structure at the top of the pumpkin.
Switch to the 3D board tool in the edit line.
On the line we just made, press the right button to select Cut.
Delete the cut part.
The pumpkin ground will be made of rectangular boards.
Add a fabric and change the color to yellow-green.
Use the edit board tool and the edit circle tool to modify the board shape.
Create a circular board that is the same size as the top of the pumpkin ground board.
Use the M-N free trim tool to select the bottom line of the pumpkin ground first.
Then press the Enter key to confirm the selection.
Then follow the order to select the top line of the pumpkin board.
Press the Enter key again to complete the trim line creation.
The same application pressure for the pumpkin ground board can make them expand.
Then you can adjust the size according to your needs.
For example, the pumpkin ground is too long, you can adjust the height of the board.
In order to make the pumpkin board effect,
we will use the ruler tool.
The ruler tool allows you to use the brush to select the position where you need to shrink.
Set the shrink rate of the ruler to negative,
and repeat several times along the side of the board.
Since the area of ​​shrink will create a fold along the border position.
Open the simulation to check the shrink effect.
To make the 3D model more realistic,
we need to divide it into more details.
In Marvelous Designer,
you need to set a smaller particle diameter to increase the detail.
Reduce the particle diameter to 5.
Since I added some uneven lines,
it will cause the pressure to be unbalanced.
This is why the pumpkin will start to fly after opening the simulation.
To solve this problem,
I need to use the fixed needle tool to fix the bottom of the pumpkin.
In the list of selected grid tools,
find the fixed needle tool.
In the 2D window,
search for the grid at the bottom.
When the shrink rate is positive,
the brushed grid will be magnified.
We can not only use this method
to create more fold effects in the middle position of the pumpkin board,
but also evenly press to make the pumpkin stand up.
After the pumpkin model is completed,
let's put the pumpkin and the small house on the grid.
Form the grid in the FBX file format
and insert Maya into Marvelous Designer with the grid animation.
In the animation editor,
we can play the animation to have a look.
Insert the pumpkin project file
and place it in the right position on the card.
The other elements
are also loaded and placed in the same way.
For the house file,
because we will paste it on the card,
the board at the bottom can be deleted.
Use the fixed needle tool
to fold the bottom of the board at the bottom of the board
and the inner line of the grid.
The top of the line of the grid
is called the fixed needle in the whole line.
When selecting the fixed needle tool,
press the Ctrl key to select the frame.
You can move the fixed needle in the frame selection area.
After the fixed needle is created,
right-click on any fixed needle in the 3D window
and select all needles to be fixed to the virtual model,
so that the house will have a fixed needle
fixed to the HECA model.
Before we add more elements,
let's test the recording animation first.
In the 3D background,
right-click and select the model attribute.
Set the gravity to 0 in it
to remove the gravity in the scene.
After short simulation,
turn on the recording.
Use the multi-dimensional tool
to draw the tree trunk and tree leaf panels.
You can draw a rough shape.
We can continue to modify it later.
Select the tree trunk panel.
Right-click and select the inner pattern of the grid.
Place the inner pattern of the grid
in the corresponding position
to the outer layer of the tree leaf panel.
Through free sewing,
quickly sew the two panels together.
Select the same pattern
and place it in the same place.
Select the same starting point and end point
to create the
However, when I start the simulation,
we will see that the position of the tree trunk
is very obvious and deep.
Even if we choose to close the fold on the inner line
in the attribute editor,
we will still see that the position of the tree trunk is very obvious.
Let's delete the tree trunk line first.
The way to stick the two panels together
is to use a sewing needle.
Now the tree trunk effect on the tree leaf is not bad.
In order to keep this shape,
we can use the shape optimization for this panel.
You can use the shape optimization in the 3D window
or go to the attribute editor
and click on the shape optimization.
Then, through the sewing needle tool,
in the 2D window,
refer to the points on the inner line
and sew them together in the corresponding position.
Open the simulation and apply the sewing effect.
Next, we need to connect the tree trunk and the card.
You can create a panel as the middle link.
Create an inner rectangle on the tree trunk panel
and then create a rectangle panel.
Select a side line,
right-click on the menu,
choose to align,
open the editor and sew the line.
Draw an inner line in the middle position.
Use the folding arrangement tool
to fold it inward along the inner line position.
In the attribute editor,
set the folding angle to 90 degrees.
Put it along the fold line of the card.
Try to make the two sides even and symmetrical.
Copy the inner rectangle on the tree trunk
to the connection panel.
Then create a panel on these two inner rectangles.
It's like using double-sided tape
to stick the two panels together.
When we open the simulation,
we will find that the tree trunk panel
looks a little soft.
We can select this panel
and print it.
For the physical properties of the tree trunk,
we can select Trim Full Grain Leather
in the preset at the bottom,
and then increase the thickness of the fabric.
Then look at the inner rectangle we created,
the length and width,
and create a similar rectangle panel.
For the rectangle created,
select the panel outline expansion,
expand the subsequent folds
and paste it to the panel part on the card,
then create a new rectangle panel.
This is the result.
Then paste it to the panel part on the card,
then create the inner line for folding,
and use the line sewing tool
to sew the inner rectangle together.
After sewing,
move the panel to the right position,
and use the folding arrangement tool to fold,
and set the folding angle.
Then create a symmetrical panel,
and place the symmetrical panel
in the 2D and 3D windows.
Then fix the folding part
to the card
in the previous method.
Then we will use the Mesh function
to create the leaf effect.
Please make sure that all leaf changes
are in the center of the scene,
and that the crease point is at the bottom.
Select all leaf changes
and click Mesh.
We will set the layout type as grid,
and create a plane as the ground.
We will set the scene model
derived from Marvelous Designer
as the template,
and create a smaller plane
than the card,
to give it more detail.
From the top view,
select the grid of tree,
house,
and pumpkin at the bottom,
and delete them.
Because we don't want
leaves to pass through it.
Go back to Mesh,
and set the flat model we just created
to input grid.
Now we can see that there are only one type of leaf.
I will add an ID node.
Set the ID node to 24,
which means that our leaf
will have 24 types.
Currently,
there are only 24 leaves in our scene,
which is not enough.
Now we will increase the number of points
at the bottom of the distribution
to get more leaves.
Finally,
in order to make the movement
and rotation more diverse,
I will use signal nodes.
Before we import the leaves
into Marvelous Designer
to simulate,
in order to make it more convenient
to import the leaves back later,
I will use the color changer
as the ID
to use different colors
for the grid.
Then we will use the color changer
to separate the different leaves
into OBJ.
In Hypershade,
right-click on the material,
select the object with the material,
and then we will use
the grid of the same material
to group them together.
After we group them together,
we will import an OBJ file
into each group separately.
Back to Marvelous Designer,
we will import the leaf OBJ file
into the scene.
Set the unit to cm,
because the default unit
in Maya is cm.
In addition,
set the object type
to GARMENT
and click OK.
In the Fabric window,
we will set the color of the material
used in the loaded leaf
to the same as in Maya
to make it easier to identify them.
To make it easier for us to export,
we will separate the types of these leaves
and change the name of the material.
When importing the remaining
OBJ leaves,
repeat these steps.
Well,
the image quality is quite good.
In order to
get better results,
you need to
first of all select the
FlipJS object
and click the Huang Zijin visual Selection button.
In order to solve this problem, we need to shape these leaves.
Press Ctrl-Z to go back to the simulation.
We want to keep their shape completely, so we need to set the strength of the shape to 100.
Simulate again.
If we need to adjust the position of some leaves, we can use the sewing needle tool to sew them to the right position.
In addition, you can also adjust their position by dragging these leaf panels when opening the simulation.
Finally, we need to drag all the leaves through the structure.
We need to use the sewing needle to fix them to the card.
Use the move tool to press the W key to click on the panel, and create a fixed needle on the panel.
Do the same for each leaf.
After completion, right-click on any fixed needle and select to fix all the needles to the virtual model.
Before we record the final animation, we need to make some adjustments.
Select all leaf fabrics,
and select Trim Hardware from the preset options in the physical attribute settings at the bottom.
In the animation editor, set the quality of the simulation to animation,
and then go to the simulation attribute and set the strength to 0.
To start the simulation, change the application, and then click the record button to start recording the animation.
After finishing recording, please save a project file .
Use the Fra玥 utilizator in Marvelous Designer to blow away the leaves.
DisINAUDIBLE all Stizen
You can right-click on the Stizen,
Right-click to delete all fixed pins, or use Ctrl-W to delete all fixed pins.
I will freeze all other versions, and only let the leaves participate in the flying simulation.
These frozen objects will collide with you to participate in the simulation, and their form will not change.
You can open it via the main menu, display, environment, and display the air conditioner.
I will adjust the air conditioner to rotate the arrow to set the starting state of the air conditioner.
In the parameter editor, first, the collider is turned on to simulate the air conditioner.
Change the type to Spherical, because I want a three-dimensional blowing.
Reduce the strength of the air conditioner, increase the air flow value, now I do not turn on the simulation for the time being.
Because I hope to keep the current state at the first stitch,
do not blow directly.
Then click the record button to start recording the animation while using the blowing effect.
When recording the animation, I can move the air conditioner to change the source position and direction of the wind.
So we can create a very interesting blowing leaf effect in the 3D window.
I think that one can use this feature here.
Finally, please check the final effect of redshift.
And show it to me, please.
Thank you for your attention.
Script information and video products are listed in the description.
Please contact us to check more information on our platform.
Thanks for watching.
See you next time.
See you on the right.
bye.
Bye.